15615 29<sup>th</sup> Dr SE Mill Creek WA - 98012

# Narendran KANAGARAJ

+1 206 899 7491 narendrankanagaraj@ymail.com

#### **E**XECUTIVE SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 13+ years of experience architecting and delivering large-scale distributed systems. Demonstrated track record of driving technical excellence across organizations and reducing operational costs. Strong expertise in cloud architecture, performance optimization, and building developer platforms that scale.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

Senior SDE Amazon/AWS Apr 2015 - Present

- Proposed, prototyped, and led cross-team migration to Quarkus and GraalVM native binary, achieving 70% memory reduction and 95% startup time improvement for Monitoring agents across Database services.
- Spearheaded ElastiCache monitoring system enhancement, elevating service availability from 99.9% to 99.99% through improved recovery mechanisms and SLA calculations
- Architected and implemented Serverless ElastiCache Failover service, significantly improving write availability during failover events.
- Orchestrated migration of Kindle bookstore pages to new rendering platform, achieving 10% latency reduction.
- Designed and launched Kindle bookstore integration with Alexa, including 'Borrow from Kindle Unlimited/Prime' feature, generating over 1M customer borrows.
- Developed federated deployment solution that decoupled services from monolithic release pipeline, enabling independent team deployments and reducing prod deployment time from 1 week to 1 day.
- Created AWS CDK-based setup solution and CLI automation tool used across Kindle bookstore teams, enabling automated infrastructure generation and reducing setup time from 2 weeks to 1 hour.

### **Senior Software Engineer**

**Pramata Knowledge Solutions** 

Dec 2013 - Apr 2015

- Implemented a rule engine for auto-assignment of documents to legal team members based on configured rules eliminating tedious manual assignment.
- Implemented a system to auto-compute legal document attributes based on user configured expressions and conditions.
- Implemented background job system with scheduling capabilities based on cron to run time-consuming async tasks.
- Engineered ML-powered legal document processing system using WEKA and Random Forest, achieving 80% precision and 90% recall in title extraction significantly reducing manual effort.

Consultant Model N Aug 2011 – Dec 2013

- Lead Model N product customizations for clients Merck and Novo Nordisk.
- Developed EDI 867 document generation system for product transfers and sales reporting

## EDUCATION

Madurai, India Thiagarajar College of Engineering Aug 2007 – Apr 2011

Bachelor of Technology (Information Technology) GPA: 8.2/10

#### LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Languages: Java, Python, Ruby, JavaScript, SQL
- Cloud: AWS (extensive experience across compute, storage, database, serverless, and deployment services)
- Frameworks: Spring, Quarkus, Ruby on Rails
- Version Control: Git, SVN